

Tim Hastie

Details

Stanford

United States

6692280913

timhastie@gmail.com

Website:

timhastie.github.io

Skills

Javascript

React

MongoDB

Node

Express

HTML & CSS

SQL / MySQL

Git / GitHub

Python

Ableton

Max MSP

Affinity Designer

Hobbies

Guitar and Electronic Music

Languages

English Spanish German

Profile

I am passionate about science, learning, and technology. I have over 5 years of experience working with hundreds of students of all ages. I have taught myself how to code, and am a full stack developer with experience using JavaScript, React, Express, MongoDB, SQL, Node, HTML, CSS, and Python. I am interested in new emerging technologies, and how to incorporate them into my work, especially Chat GPT and AI. I spent several years working on music while working as an English teacher. My radio shows and tracks are available to listen to on my website as well as on streaming platforms.

Employment History

English Teacher, Italki

June 2016 - Present

- Developed creative and personalized learning plans for each student.
- Increased my ability to think on the spot and adjust lesson plans as needed.
- Extensive and thorough note taking and feedback provided for each student.
- Created my own program using Electron JS to allow students to review the vocabulary they learned during classes.

Front Desk Associate, Stanford University

September 2014 - February 2016

- Used Opera software to check and record information pertinent to reservations, guest profiles, and to open and review various reports that detail information on room statuses, arrivals, credit limits, journal of transactions, rate checks, etc.
- Created reservations for guests, and performed audits to verify guest billing information, payment processing, and finding and correcting discrepancies from previous days work.
- Corresponded with guests via email and phone, as well as helped them with any questions they had about the area, the hotel, or life in general.

Education

B.A in Anthropology, University of California, Santa Cruz

September 2012 - June 2014

- My degree was a comprehensive overview of human culture and history, in which I studied many human cultures around the world, from the past until present, and how their institutions, beliefs, and cultural practices helped them and sometimes hindered them in their ability to adapt to their surrounding environments.
- The courses I took have broadened my perspective and helped give me the tools to understand, be accepting of, and work with people from various backgrounds and cultures.

Extra-curricular activities

Radio Host, Hamshack Radio, Cape Town

July 2021 - November 2022

- Created mixes each month for my radio show called "Blender" on Hamshack Radio in Cape Town, South Africa. It was a fun experience in which I was able to share music I love with those around me, as well as meet others passionate about music. Many of my radio shows were recorded and are available to listen to on my personal website.
- A musical piece I made called Sound Log 8 was published on vinyl via a record label called City Bowl Wax Network. The track was made using field recordings made in Kirstenbosch park, South Africa. It is available to stream or buy online on most platforms, as well as on my website.
- I have made several devices using Max MSP, a visual programming environment which can be used to build musical tools and instruments, as well as other creative tools for experimental media. They are available to download on my website
- While learning how to use technologies like React and Express, I have made several projects which are available to view and use on my website. These include a drum machine made with React, my dads website using Mongo DB and express, and various other projects.